{
  "id": "java_quizz01",
  "description": "Java Programming Fundamentals Quiz",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What are the fundamental building blocks of the Java language?",
      "answers": [
        "Variables, data types, control structures, methods, and classes",
        "Functions, arrays, loops, and objects",
        "Pointers, structs, and memory allocation",
        "CSS, HTML, JavaScript, and PHP"
      ],
      "correct": [0]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of a Java data type?",
      "answers": ["int", "float", "string", "all of the above"],
      "correct": [0, 1]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a Java method?",
      "answers": [
        "To define a new class",
        "To declare a variable",
        "To perform a specific task or action",
        "To create an object"
      ],
      "correct": [2]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which control flow structure in Java is used to execute a block of code repeatedly?",
      "answers": ["if-else", "switch-case", "while loop", "for loop"],
      "correct": [2, 3]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the concept of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) in Java?",
      "answers": [
        "It is a programming paradigm that focuses on objects and classes",
        "It involves writing code without using objects",
        "It is only applicable to scripting languages",
        "It&#39;s a technique to optimize code execution"
      ],
      "correct": [0]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT an OOP concept in Java?",
      "answers": ["Class", "Interface", "Object", "Array"],
      "correct": [3]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a Java interface?",
      "answers": [
        "To define a blueprint for classes to implement",
        "To represent a concrete implementation of a class",
        "To store data",
        "To perform mathematical operations"
      ],
      "correct": [0]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement accurately describes Java syntax?",
      "answers": [
        "Java is case-sensitive",
        "Java does not support object-oriented programming",
        "Java allows the use of the &#39;goto&#39; statement",
        "Java variables do not need to be declared before they are used"
      ],
      "correct": [0]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the &#39;this&#39; keyword in Java?",
      "answers": [
        "To refer to the current class instance",
        "To create a new object",
        "To define a constant",
        "To specify the superclass"
      ],
      "correct": [0]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a valid Java class declaration?",
      "answers": [
        "class MyClass { }",
        "MyClass = new Class()",
        "class = new MyClass()",
        "class { }"
      ],
      "correct": [0]
    }
  ]
}
